the 10:00 a.m. dump. Some of the futures
for Bitcoin and other digital assets
have a very important time at which
their value is is struck at London's, I
believe it's 10:00 a.m. here or 11:00
a.m. Another important timeline for
these products is 4:00 p.m. in the US.
That's when NAV is struck, and you see a
lot of trading activity between 3:00 and
4:00 for that reason. As the ETFs become
a financial instrument, they're used for
institutional investment, they're used
for hedging. You can go long, you can go
short. And going short doesn't even
necessarily mean that you think, you
know, Bitcoin is done. It's just that
Would you see why retail investors would
think that is so-called unfair?
In the most progressive of worlds, we
would have one global currency.
>> TSMC has been the biggest stock in
Taiwan. And they're also trading in the
US, so TSM. If I own TSM, do I own a
piece of the company, too? Sometimes
they trade very differently.
>> Markets are open during different times,
and there can be extended holidays in
some Asian countries. My guess is that
this happens during times when those
markets are closed, and the US product
becomes a way to continue to express
your view. This surprised us. Uh we've
recently seen that whales have
increasingly been interested in putting
their tokens into the ETF. Hype and BNB
are two that I'm keeping my eye on.
>> Would you see a scenario in which a
future Federal Reserve could buy Bitcoin
ETFs during a distressed period?
>> I think it's
a conversation you had about Taiwan
extreme. Yes.
>> Talking about the future of
institutional adoption and tokenization
with Kristie Lyn Senior Vice President
of ETF Capital Markets at Grayscale
Investments. Welcome to the show,
Kristie. Good to
>> Thanks so much for having me. I am super
excited to talk to you. Uh could you
comment on the
earlier event of um the 10:00 a.m. dump.
So, people are speculating that every
day at 10:00 a.m. Bitcoin would have
this uh 2 to 3% sell-off, and then
retails were would pour in, and then
that's the whole thing between AP and
then the ETF issuers. What is that
about?
>> Yeah, I know that there have been some
theories, Twitter or X of course have
latched on to this. I don't necessarily
know what exactly drives it, but to me
there's a couple things that are
indicative or significant, and that has
to do with certain NAV strikes and
certain other financial instruments that
have important times at around that
time.
As an example, some of the futures for
Bitcoin and other digital assets have a
very important time at which their value
is is struck at London's, I believe it's
10:00 a.m. here or 11:00 a.m. here. So,
that kind of correlates with the
timeline that you're mentioning. Now,
another important timeline for these
products is 4:00 p.m. in the US, that's
when NAV is struck, and you see a lot of
trading activity between 3:00 and 4:00
for that reason.
So, I think, you know, we do a lot of
debunking of some of the theories out
there, especially for Grayscale when
people see tokens moving in or out of
wallets and they're speculating, we're
buying or selling, we're just
facilitating a settlement. And my guess
is that this is something similar where
those are important times for
determining value
that may inspire a lot of trading, but
there's not a lot of deeper meaning
behind it.
>> And there are people talking about,
you know, the data. So, retail
investors, they look at the inflows and
outflows of Bitcoin spot ETF, and
they're like, oh, institutions are
buying or selling. But there are a lot
of ways to hedge against that. Could you
comment on that?
>> Yeah, exactly. So, when we have a
settlement for our Bitcoin or other
digital asset ETF, you can see movements
of Bitcoin or whatever token it is on
the blockchain coming into and out of
our wallets. And like you said, people
often assume that Grayscale is actively
making a decision to buy or sell. We are
really beholden to the end investor who
seeks to buy shares and ultimately that
makes its way to an authorized
participant who may create or redeem.
Now, when they do that creation or
redemption, my team actually will go out
and buy Bitcoin or sell Bitcoin
commensurate to the number of shares
created or redeemed. We're not taking an
active management approach, you know,
it's really just driven off of the needs
of the market. Now, you also mentioned
hedging and that's an important point,
too.
I think that as the ETFs become a
financial instrument, as we like to call
it, basically a bellwether
representation of the asset class and I
think they've arrived at that kind of
stature, uh they're not just used for
speculative investment. They're used for
institutional investment, they're used
for hedging. You can go long, you can go
short. And and going short doesn't even
necessarily mean that you think, you
know, Bitcoin is done. It's just that
you're taking an investment thesis and
you're applying it through the Bitcoin
ETF.
>> I remember when I first started covering
the space before Bitcoin ETFs were first
rolled out, the Grayscale GBTC was the
gold standard for institutional adoption
of um
securitized products. Now, at the time,
people used a discount or premium to NAV
as a really close indicator to
sentiment.
>> Yes.
>> Can you, before we comment on that
aspect, just comment on why premiums or
discounts happen?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, so a premium or a discount is ETFs
treatment to markets. Uh you or I would
trade on the secondary market that's
going into our Fidelity or Schwab
account and buying shares. But ETFs also
trade on an institutional level on the
primary market and that's when something
called an authorized participant goes
directly to the ETF market maker and
creates new shares or removes existing
shares from the market. Now, premiums
and discounts happen when that secondary
market price does not equal the NAV,
which is the primary market price. And
typically, the authorized participant,
really an ETF market maker who's working
with an authorized participant will keep
those two very, very tight. Now, in
cases of GBTC before it was an ETF,
it did not have the primary market
function. And so, ETF market makers
could only access one side of that
market, and therefore, they couldn't
keep it really tight with the share
price and the NAV. Now, why was that
something that people tracked so
heavily? It was because the premium and
discount almost became an indicator of
market sentiment about probability of us
winning our lawsuit and being able to
convert it into an ETF. Because they
knew that if we could convert it, that
would allow this mechanism to really
work as it's designed to work, and share
price should become NAV. So, every time
there was a significant piece of news,
you can see the premium or discount
abruptly drop or abruptly increase as
the market would digest what they
thought it meant for the probability
that these products would be approved
for ETF form.
>> But even at this time, Bitcoin was a
very liquid market. Why didn't
arbitrageurs completely eliminate this
discount or premium all the time?
>> Yeah, so they do now. So, if you see the
Bitcoin ETFs, the premiums and discounts
are in the single digit basis points,
which is very, very small. Now, at the
time before GBTC was able to uplist or
turn into an ETF, that premium or
discount could be like 10, 20%, which is
really unheard of for ETFs. And the
reason for that was because arbitrageurs
could not access the primary market.
They could only trade on the secondary
market. So, there was a surplus of
shares in market that really had no
outlet to be reduced.
>> How does centralized exchange play in
this whole uh scene?
>> Yeah, I think that uh they are very
important as an outlet to trade. So,
like I said, when we get a creation or a
redemption, we have to go buy Bitcoin or
sell Bitcoin. Now, for Grayscale, we
work directly bilaterally with certain
trading institutions, but there are some
issuers that rely on some of the
exchanges as another venue for accessing
that liquidity.
And ultimately, we call them liquidity
providers, the traders that we work with
are also tied into that ecosystem. So,
it's very symbiotic, whether you're
trading directly with the liquidity
provider, they're probably sourcing some
token on these exchanges, or they're
providing their own liquidity on
exchange, and really all of that funnels
into the very tight pricing that these
ETFs are able to command.
>> Could you walk us through the sequence?
What happens when I buy a share of
Bitcoin spot ETF? What happens behind
the scene?
>> I love this question. This is what I
spend most of my time on. So, you know,
you and other investors are going to go
out and buy Bitcoin ETFs. Now,
eventually there's enough market demand
for an ETF market maker who is behind
the scenes providing you with those
shares, that they are becoming short.
So, they're selling you the shares, they
might not necessarily have them though.
In order to go cover that, they need to
create new shares. So, they're going to
work with an authorized participant,
which is a institution that has certain
licenses to engage directly with an
issuer like Grayscale.
They're going to bundle that short that
they have, and they're going to come to
Grayscale and say, "I need to create
shares to cover this short that I've
established." Now, my team is going to
say,
"Okay, how many shares do you need?"
Translate that into a quantity of
Bitcoin, and then go purchase that
amount of Bitcoin in the market to
actually back those shares with a
commensurate amount of Bitcoin. When
that all settles, the ETF market maker,
through their authorized participant, is
going to get those shares, and you've
already gotten your shares. You know,
you're you're This is all happening
under the hood, behind the scenes. You
are good to go, but that will really
complete the life cycle when the
authorized participant delivers shares
to the ETF market maker and covers their
short. And they're doing this day in,
day out, so we see creations and
redemptions on an ongoing, continuous
basis throughout the day.
>> And that process takes a day, or
>> takes about a day to settle, but the
trade itself is very quick. It might
take 5, 10 minutes, and that's by
design. We want to make sure that
markets are not moving while the
authorized participant is seeking their
pricing. And as you know, very liquid
markets a piece of news can move a
market a lot. So, we intentionally move
very quickly through this process.
>> Just a quick follow-up on that. I think
the argument um
the news that I was referring to
the argument was that there are APs that
are also liquidity providers and
This is true.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, to elaborate a little
bit more on that, the authorized
participant role is technically a US
broker-dealer. I think a lot of people
get confused that the authorized
participant is the one kind of pulling
the strings and making the uh decision
to create or redeem. But, they're really
more of an
more of an administrative function.
The brains behind the operation is an
ETF market maker. Now, a lot of ETF
market makers also within their broader
company have crypto trading enterprises.
And so, we do typically see a lot of
pairing off between ETF market makers
sending in orders through their
authorized participant. When I go out
and do that trade to buy Bitcoin
we often see their crypto desk winning
that trade. And that's very uh very much
by design by that ETF market maker
because they can collapse their risk
that way. If you think about hedging a
trade, if you have the ETF shares, you
probably also want to match the Bitcoin
exposure and they can collapse their
risk by winning the Bitcoin trade.
>> But, would you see why retail investors
would think that is so-called unfair?
It's like, you know, you guys are the
smart money and we can't beat that.
>> I think potentially, but how I would
refute that is the end investor benefits
from it actually by getting very tight
spreads in market. And what I mean by
that is when you or I go to buy a
Bitcoin ETF, the spread, so the bid and
the ask, is typically 1 cent. That's as
tight as it can possibly get. That's
single digit basis, and that's very,
very good pricing.
Now, that's possible because the ETF
market makers are able to have these
efficiencies. You or I can't access the
primary market, and I do think that's
where a lot of these kind of theories
come from, but we do ultimately benefit
from it because authorized participants
have to engage in huge blocks of shares
that we're probably not interested in
trading that much, uh but we benefit
from their very tight spreads. So, it is
very much an ecosystem where everyone is
aligned to have the you know, the best
outcome possible, and I I can see where
some of these theories come from, but
hopefully I've debunked it. I love that.
>> So, Grayscale Research reported that
across six crypto sectors including um
I'll just pull them up here.
Uh they including financials and um
and ETFs, we have negative returns um
throughout quarter 1 and 2.
Now,
uh at the same time, tokenization volume
increased by 245%.
So, tell us about these counter trends
here.
>> Mhm. Yeah, so recently I have seen the
biggest themes of my conversations being
more about infrastructure build than
price appreciation. And I think that's
kind of indicative of the
mature maturation of the industry that
we're seeing.
I think instead of talking about a token
that might 10x in the next few weeks or
months, we're talking about what is the
actual infrastructure that we're
building on the blockchain. And to me, I
think that speaks to what we're going to
be able to build in the future. We're
talking about banks potentially using
stablecoins. We're talking about
tokenizing assets so we can trade on a
24/7 basis and bring some of the
principles of digital asset investing to
the mainstream US markets. Um so,
instead of it being about price
appreciation, and as you noted, it can
actually be prices going down in some
cases, I think there's so much progress
being made behind the scenes to really
implement the true spirit of blockchain
technology.
>> So, of the six crypto sectors
researched, currencies, smart contract
platforms, financials, consumers,
artificial intelligence, and utilities
and services, which of these do you
think still have the most growth
potential for the remainder of the year?
>> So, I am more token agnostic than some
might be. I personally think that
picking stocks or picking tokens is very
very challenging to do. So, I gravitate
towards index products that kind of
encapsulate all of them. We do have one
product that's the top five tokens by
market cap excluding meme coins and
stable coins, and we've measured that
that can actually capture 90% of the
returns of the crypto market. So, while
some people are more into picking the
right token, picking the right sector, I
don't even do this with stocks. I buy
the S&P 500.
To me, that's kind of the analog of the
S&P 500 and how I approach the
investment.
>> I'd like to get you to react to your
former boss's comments, Larry Fink, on
tokenization. I'll play this on the
screen as well.
>> You know, I do believe we're just at the
beginning of the tokenization of all
assets from real estate
to equities, to bonds, across the board.
Um there is
>> BlackRock has a $10 trillion
tokenization vision, but broadly
speaking, why do we need what he said,
which is the tokenization of all assets?
>> Yeah, I don't disagree with him,
especially his points that we're at the
very early innings. Um I think and and a
theme that's come up here, particularly
at this conference, is the convergence
of TradFi and DeFi. We're here in suits.
Like, I never thought that would happen
at a consensus. Uh and to me,
tokenization is kind of the continuation
of that. So,
we were talking earlier. I see
tokenization or I see stablecoins as
kind of tokenized cash, and I think
that's the first place that we'll see
banks and other really traditional
finance institutions getting their
foothold. That can next progress to
tokenizing something basic like a US
equity. There you gain the benefits of
digital asset features like 24/7
trading, instantaneous settlement, and
we were also talking about borderless
ability to invest. So, if I'm in another
country, but I want to buy a US equity,
tokenization can really enable that.
Now, I think there are naysayers that
are like, "This isn't that novel. It's
not taking it that far." And so you
bring up real estate. I think that
things like that will be a very
different application. I think it's
going to be years before we see
mainstream adoption of that and really
that is the focus of tokenization, but I
do think that eventually that's where
we're going to go. But it's baby steps.
We're starting with cash, we're going to
get to equities, and then we'll move on
to more advanced underliers.
>> You know how nations sometimes they want
to protect how their own currency flow,
where they go.
How does tokenization
change that? Yeah, I had a great
conversation with someone working on a
payments company last night about this.
I think it could threaten them in some
ways and you do see with tokenization
rules about who can invest in what even
in the US we can't necessarily invest in
all the tokenization representations of
US equities and I think that there are
protections that countries will want to
put in place to keep their currencies a
little bit more centralized. But now you
could also say that Bitcoin has broken
down those barriers because Bitcoin of
course is a global currency. So I think
regulation is needed in order to
understand what can and cannot be built
in certain regions and I think that will
help practitioners really move forward
with confidence.
>> But I want I want to push on that a
little further. In let's say 20 years,
we look back. What would change?
>> Well, I think that's going to come down
to geopolitics honestly. What are
countries going to be comfortable with
and what are they going to allow? I
think in the most progressive of worlds
we would have one global currency, but I
don't think that will get there anytime
soon. There are real reasons why central
banks want to you know control and
protect their monetary system and so I
don't necessarily see us moving to a
place where countries are comfortable
with widespread adoption of any
currency, but I do think that we'll see
more
FX trading of some of these assets. We
already see it in some cases with
different Bitcoin USD, Bitcoin other
currency pairs and I could see us moving
to a world where we have a more
globalized currency and then there is
this need for FX trading to convert to
those countries that are kind of the
holdouts.
>> So tokenize real assets. Now, a lot of
those have been sold as promises to the
individual investor as retaining the
ownership right to that particular
asset. So, say let's say I like music.
>> Okay.
>> A Stradivari violin that is tokenized.
Uh many people who can own tokenized
shares of that violin will have a say in
how the violin is used and performed.
That's just one example of a real world
asset. How does that translate to
stocks? How does ownership work for
stocks? Let's So, for the sake of
argument, let's say Crystal Lynch Co.
has 100 shares outstanding.
>> Yep.
>> For the sake of argument, Bonnie share
Bonnie owns 100 shares of your company.
So, she's the largest shareholder of
your company. There's 100 tokenized
shares on each of these shares. I own
the tokenized shares. So, who owns your
company now?
>> Yeah, so there's a lot of analogies here
with ETFs as well, which is the area
that I work in. And that goes with the
ownership rights and voting rights. So,
for example, ETFs have even had to
grapple with this. Like, if I own shares
of an ETF, do I get to vote to say that
I want one of the shares within my S&P
500 of 500 shares, uh do I get to make
the managerial decision? And I think
this is very reminiscent of that
quandary uh that ETFs have faced. Now,
there's another piece of it that goes a
step further, which is in the tokenized
representation, do you even own the
underlying stock or do you own an IOU?
And so, these are some of the regulatory
issues that we're really grappling with
right now to understand who owns what,
who has rights to what. Uh and I will
say an analog that we see is the
difference between a US ETF and some of
the European ETNs or ETPs have similar,
I would say, technicalities. Uh in some
cases, in a European product, you
actually own shares or own rights to the
issuer, not the underlying assets. And
so, that's an analog that I study to see
how that's been dealt with in other
regions for traditional assets. And I
think that you know, we spend a lot of
our time looking at traditional analogs
to kind of guide and opine on what we
think the way should be for digital
assets. So, I wouldn't be surprised if
there's the need for roundtables and
other kind of thought leadership to look
at these real-world examples and help
guide the path forward till there is
clarity on those questions.
>> What is your personal view? What do you
think it should be?
>> That's a good one. I haven't really
applied enough time researching it to
have a stance because I think it also
has to do with the mechanics of how the
product works.
If you're going direct on chain, then I
think there's probably more of an
argument for you to be able to make that
decision and have that discretion versus
if you're using a system where maybe the
shares are still in custody at a big
financial institution and you just own
the IOU, then I think that's more like
the ETF model I described where
potentially the institution tokenizing
it and giving you that IOU should retain
some more discretion just for
administrative purposes.
>> Just another quick question. Um TSMC has
been the biggest stock in Taiwan. And
they're also they're also trading in the
US. So, TSM.
>> Okay.
>> If I
if I own TSM, do I own a piece of the
company, too? Or how does that work?
>> It depends on how it's gotten to the US.
So, there's something called an ADR
that's a popular right, a popular way to
get a US equities to other countries and
vice versa. So, now it really depends on
the structuring. I'd have to look into
the specifics of this, but my guess is
that you don't actually own the
underlying share. It is possible that
you do, it's possible. You always have
to read the prospectus, you know, the
devil's in the details.
But this is another example of a
wrapper. So, ETFs are a wrapper, tokens
are a wrapper, ADRs are a wrapper. And
again, they're another way that we study
how these things are actually working
today in US financial systems and
abroad. And how can we digitize it?
There are these examples in market for
us to study.
>> Wrappers, do they track the underlying
asset? Because sometimes they trade very
differently. Sometimes, you know, the
ADR in US would be up 15% but in Taiwan
only 10. So I'm just trying to
understand cuz I own both.
>> Yep. Yep. So, the wrapper, if it's
working the way it's supposed to, it
should be perfect one-to-one matching.
And that goes back to the GD the GBTC
example that we talked about earlier.
The premium or discount existed because
it was not working the way that it was
designed to work. It could not access
the primary market. So, therefore, there
was dislocation.
My guess is, in this case, since those
markets are open during different times
and there can be extended holidays in
some Asian countries, my guess is that
this happens during times when those
markets are closed and the US product
becomes a way to continue to express
your view even though markets in Asia
are closed.
>> Mhm. I love that.
>> Okay, so
early April, uh US spot Bitcoin ETFs
recorded 173.7
million dollars in net outflows as of
April 1st. Grayscale, however, the
lower-cost mini trust BTC attracted
10.25 million dollars in inflows. How
did Grayscale buck the trend?
>> We love it. Uh
So, we have studied this a lot. We were
very pleased to see that pattern. We
believe that because we are the
lowest-cost vehicle in market that we
have a stickier investor base. So,
instead of being a lot of speculative
investors who are just in it for a quick
expression of inflow, outflow, inflow,
outflow, we think that we get a lot of
people who really have conviction on the
asset class and want to be in it for the
long haul. So, they're less sensitive to
news that might be short-lived. Uh they
stay in the product and so even when our
competitors are seeing outflows,
oftentimes we see our investors sticking
with us.
>> Is the profile different? Your investor
profiles are different.
>> I think it could be in the sense that it
again is kind of this more long hold, I
have conviction in digital assets, I
have conviction in Bitcoin type investor
as opposed to more speculative risk on
risk off where you're trying to make a
quick call and put on
you know, some sort of exposure because
you think in the next 5 minutes maybe
there's going to be some way to capture
value and those flows can be very
volatile. They're not necessarily sticky
investors and the low management fee
really commands the investor type that
is looking to be in it for the long
haul.
>> Ether ETF's interestingly closed Q1 with
a $769 million quarterly outflow, their
worst 3-month stretch since launching.
However,
Grayscale's ETHE the ETHE product
attracted capital despite a higher 2.5%
fee. What does that tell you about
institutional appetite?
>> So one thing that differentiates our
Ethereum products especially at that
time was that we implemented staking. So
our Ethereum products actually yield,
they have value that they provide to
investors for staking. Now for those who
don't know what staking is, I'm sure you
guys know, it's basically when you put
your assets to work and you're paid in
kind for that kind of contribution of
assets. The thing that was hard to solve
for with that implementation
was while you stake your assets, they're
not liquid. And so if you need to be
able to honor a redemption, so that
would be me needing to sell Ethereum in
this case to provide cash to our
authorized participant, then I can't
necessarily do that with staked assets.
So we had to develop a very robust
framework for how we could measure what
is enough liquidity in the fund, how
much can we stake and really monitor
that on an ongoing basis. We went to the
SEC and showed them our model. So it was
a long time coming to be able to
implement this and we ultimately
implemented it very late last year in
October. But it is a differentiator for
our products. Our ETHE product actually
pays out a distribution so investors get
a cash distribution. Our ETH product
reinvests those rewards, so it has some
accruing kind of nature to it. And I
think that that could be a reason why
investors stuck with us during a period
of outflows.
>> Okay, on yield, you know how there was a
big debate right now currently on Wall
Street between
how banks can
tolerate, let's say, stablecoins issuing
a yield. Can you as Grayscale or any
other of your peers design a derivative
product of a stablecoin that has a
native yield embedded? Because that
would be really interesting for
investors.
>> Yeah, so one thing we've done to to give
yield to our investors is actually our
covered call strategies. Um so we're
using options overlays in order to build
yield on top of Bitcoin positions and
Ethereum positions. So aside from
staking, which we can do on a number of
protocols we deliver in ETF form, we can
also provide uh yield through these
synthetic kind of products that are
really using options overlays in order
to develop that yield for investors.
>> Mhm.
And final question on this particular
subject from me. Can you comment on
which of the tokens on Grayscale's
watchlist, expanded watchlist, gets an
ETH wrapper this year?
>> Uh gets an ETF wrapper, yes. So we have
a couple active filings right now. I
won't elaborate further beyond the
protocols, but uh Hype and BNB are two
that I'm keeping my eye on.
>> Awesome.
>> How do you decide which coin?
So there was a period of time where it
was really dictated by regulation. You
know, we had Bitcoin available to us,
then we had Ethereum available to us,
and then there was this explosion in the
number of filings that issuers were
putting in front of the SEC. And that
led them to have to crank through so
many filings, I think they had 90 at one
point, that they developed something
called the generic listing standards.
And this is the framework by which
issuers understand if a token can be ETP
eligible. Now, that has kind of
encapsulated, I'd say, about 15
different tokens at this point, but it's
a growing list. And And led us to this
crossroads where you have to be
selective now. Instead of it being like,
okay, we can so we will, we have to
apply more discretion and be more
selective about what assets we bring to
market in ETF form. So, we now offer
eight tokens in ETF form, soon to be
several more. Uh but to answer your
question, we have a research team that
does a lot of diligence on protocols,
gets to meet the team, and they spend
years doing this. Uh they really come up
with their investment thesis and
cultivate relationships, understand what
the protocols are all about, and they
overlay on top of the regulatory can I,
they overlay that should I. And so, we
work in lockstep with our uh research
team to really develop our investment
thesis and push forward particular
protocols.
>> You mentioned BNB and HYPE. So, HYPE
does not have VC.
Is that like a consideration that you
guys make? BNB also, it's very
distributed.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
do you prefer not to pick those tokens
with large whales?
>> Um not necessarily, and I think that the
whale point is very interesting for the
ETFs because we've recently seen, and
this surprised us, uh we've recently
seen that whales have increasingly been
interested in putting their tokens into
the ETF. We thought that as a crypto
native, that would be kind of repugnant
to get on the US rails uh via the ETF,
but the reason that it's compelling is
because if you move your token into
shares format,
you can oftentimes get tax planning,
estate planning, uh the benefits that
these kind of US brokerage accounts
allow. You can generally also use your
shares for margin and collateral, which
can be also quite compelling. Um so,
we've had recent progress with actually
whales wanting the ETF because then
they're able to put their token into it
to access some of these features.
>> Could you share with me, how does that
work? So, let's say I'm a whale of
whatever token, I come to you and I say
I want to convert that into ETFs.
>> Yes, generally that is how it works. So,
behind the scenes, of course, there's a
lot going on, but yes, my team will
actually work directly with whales. We
will engage with our authorized
participant partners or other
third-party intermediaries to help them
in kind tokens into the product. So we
talked earlier about the cash creation
redemption process. Last summer, the SEC
decided that it would be okay to do in
kind creation redemption, and that
really opened the doors for this type of
investor.
Now, my team, instead of going out and
trading,
we will instead kind of hold the hands
of all the third parties necessary to
move token from a whale's account into
our trust and issue shares to them in
response.
>> So for people that do not understand
what this means,
if you buy a a share of spot ETF,
>> Mhm.
>> uh you would have had to go on the
market and buy a share, but now you can
Now I can go to you and give you
>> Exactly.
>> And that changed last year, you said.
>> Yes, that's right. So now you would
actually be accessing the primary
market. So we talked about those two
markets. Primary markets are almost
never available to individual investors
because of this authorized participant
requirement. Uh but we have some very
clever authorized participants who have
opened the doors for individual
investors to partner with them to do
this.
>> Now that we have 2 years of data for
Bitcoin ETFs, the spot ETF,
have you noticed a
correlation between outflows and inflows
and the subsequent price movement? In
other words, what comes first usually,
the outflows and inflows of the ETF
>> Yeah.
>> and selling of the underlying?
>> This is a great question and something
that we studied for our staking model
because we did need to explain to the
SEC, if you have an abrupt price change,
especially in a volatile asset, is it
going to lead to chaos with redemptions?
Um and we found that, of course, there's
some correlation, but it's not
necessarily one that's indicative of the
other. And I think that the ETFs are
really good and efficient way to express
a view on risk very quickly. So you can
see it go inflows quickly to outflows
the next day.
And I think that's because of the
efficiency of the vehicle. Now, of
course, when the price is going up, you
typically see creation demand. Uh, when
the price is going down, you typically
see redemption demand. So, they do
generally align, but I would say one is
not a leading in indicator of the other.
Uh, if anything, it might skew a little
bit towards the price being what you
see, uh, a delayed reaction to with the
ETFs, but it's not like you know it's
going to happen because you're seeing
one versus the other.
>> If more and more Bitcoins get bought up
by treasury companies, would that skew
the creation redemption process? Would
there be less liquidity for you to
actually, you know,
use that mechanism?
>> We get this question a lot, especially
with the cap on Bitcoin of 21 million.
That's another, you know, people say,
"Oh, no, are we going to run out of
Bitcoin?" And really, it should just
push up the price of Bitcoin with basic
supply demand, uh, you know, dynamics.
It will not hinder the creation
redemption process. It just means that
buying Bitcoin might cost more, but that
manifests in a higher price of Bitcoin,
and the NAV moves alongside that. The
actual execution costs, I would not
expect it to be higher.
>> Back to tokenization, I think the debate
last year we had was, um,
how do you make sure that a token
represent, let's say, 1% of that real
estate?
>> Yeah.
>> Um, is it
a country that has to come out and say,
"Okay, we are going to verify this?" Or
what's what has to happen?
>> Yeah, I think this is one of those
ambiguities that has to be solved before
there can be success. I think there
needs to be some sort of, you know,
right rules and regulations or
guidelines about how you determine the
value. But this is not that dissimilar
from, again, going back to traditional
finance analogs, uh, whenever there's
ambiguity about a price, like an index,
will have a very robust set of rules by
which you determine a waterfall of
pricing. And there can be instances when
you challenge that price. For example,
you could say, "I typically price this
using a Bloomberg index, but today I
don't agree with that because it's this
percentage away from the last trade
price.
Um
those will actually go to disputes, and
we do see that system working as it's
supposed to. Uh there can be frictions,
but of course healthy frictions, and I
think that this is where we'll
ultimately have to go with something
like tokenization as well. You know,
there has to be some sort of either
golden source of truth or board that can
come to a consensus. Uh so more to come
on that. That's going to be one of the
things necessary to make this work, but
like I said, I think baby steps. We
start with cash, we go to equities,
ultimately we'll go to real world
assets.
>> Is there a timeline?
>> I think it'll be years for real world
assets. I think we already see adoption
for cash right now in stable coins. My
guess is many banks are using them
behind the scenes whether they're vocal
about it or not. And I think with
equities, there are a number of US
institutions like NYSE, Nasdaq, the DTC
that have come out with announcements
about projects. Um so I think that we'll
see progress on that in the in the
coming months. I think that's right
ahead of us, uh but how far it goes, I
think it'll be uh it'll be a build that
takes a couple years.
>> The Federal Reserve has had a history of
buying ETFs, especially during
emergencies like COVID, more so on the
corporate bond side. Would you see a
scenario in which a future Federal
Reserve could buy Bitcoin ETFs during a
distressed period?
>> I think it's possible, you know, don't
say anything's impossible, but uh it is
it seems to me like they'll still need
more time to get comfortable with the
asset class. Uh but we I guess, you
know, again harping on my analogies
here.
>> the Fed be comfortable enough?
>> Uh I think he's going to take a little
bit more time.
>> Okay.
>> But you know, you see pensions and
endowments starting to do it, and I
think that that's kind of the first
sign. Bitcoin is becoming so much more
institutional. I think we talk to a lot
of people at Grayscale who are just
beginning their crypto journey. They're
new to it, but here, you know, of course
we're like everyone should have it,
everyone has it, and we just assume
that's the case.
Um so I think there is quite a continuum
of investors out there, but I do has in
their portfolio.
>> Is Bitcoin becoming more and more
institutional and less exciting?
>> I hate to say less exciting, but I do
think it is becoming more institutional.
You know, just looking around the crowd
today at Consensus, it's a lot more
traditional banks, it's a lot more
people in suits.
And and that's exciting in and of itself
because it means that there's maturity
of the asset class. Ultimately, that's
going to bring more investors as we open
the doors for people that were sitting
on the sidelines. The ETFs were a huge
part of that for people that didn't know
how to open a wallet, institutions that
didn't have the risk, you know,
infrastructure to manage a wallet or
didn't want to build that out. So I
think that while it is less exciting in
some ways, I think it's very exciting in
the sense that it is getting more
adoption and it's getting more
institutionalized.
>> How do you react to all these Bitcoin
OGs
prediction on Bitcoin going to a million
dollars or you know, a crazy high
number?
>> I mean, I hope they're right.
I think that there are again supply
demand dynamics that could make that a
reality. Now a million dollars is very
high.
I think it's going to take some time to
get there. But if we look at some of the
things like the 21 million dollar cap,
we look at dads and ETFs that are buying
these, we look at new investors that
have come into the fold because of the
ability to invest through the ETF, those
are all kind of positive tailwinds that
should push the price up.
>> the solution to the problem you're
talking about making this exciting is to
institutionalize meme coins. There's a
big PP stand over there
with the frogs, so maybe there's a
partnership there.
All right, well, so the future of
Bitcoin and ETH this year, which do you
think um
What do you think they go towards the
end of the year?
>> So I think to me Bitcoin represents
the
all of the above for blockchain, for
Bitcoin, for other digital assets. We
work with a lot of people that are new
to the investment in digital asset
world. And so, a lot of them are just
learning about Bitcoin, and I think that
that's what they gravitate to. It's like
they might have heard of Bitcoin and
other, they're not necessarily able to
go down the token spectrum yet. So, to
me, Bitcoin, I think, is very compelling
for that reason because so many
investors gravitate to it for their
first experience. Now, Ethereum, I get
really excited about because I think the
value or a lot of value is in these
smart contract type builds. I think that
being able to use blockchain technology
to improve
our processes and codify, if you think
about fixed income bond, codify some of
these back office functions, make things
more efficient. I think that's really
exciting. So, to me, I think Bitcoin and
Ethereum both have very bright futures,
but for slightly different reasons.
>> Awesome.
>> I want to talk about Ethereum. Earlier
you mentioned staked ETF. Could you
elaborate or tell my mom, explain to my
mom,
how does that work? How do you stake
ETH, but also get the yield? How
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, we work with third-party validators
who are that a validator is basically
who you are pledging, and you know,
pledging's not the right terminology,
but we'll use it here to simplify
things.
You're contributing your tokens to make
the overall protocols more safe and
secure. Now, as you have it pledged, it
is locked up, it's not liquid. And so,
that is the conundrum that we faced in
implementing this for a very liquid
product. So, you're pledging your assets
in order to make the
the greater good of the ecosystem, and
in turn you're paid in kind. So, you'll
actually get a deposit in your wallet of
that same asset, in this case, Ethereum.
Now, how we deal with that is for our EV
product, we actually monetize that. So,
I'll go out and trade that, raise cash,
and pay that out to our investors. In
the case of ETH, we will then stake that
Ethereum that we've received, so it
compounds over time. Now, how do we deal
with the illiquidity aspect of this? Uh,
we've through some very, uh, intense
mathematical modeling, we've determined
what we think should remain unstaked in
the fund, and we dynamically calibrate
that based on market conditions. Now, we
additionally have implemented something
called delayed settlement with some of
our liquidity providers, uh, where
they're able to give us cash on a T+1
basis, and we will settle token to them
once available. And of course, they'll
charge a little bit of a spread for
that, but it makes the product more
efficient and allows us to get yield, so
ultimately, the overall economics
benefit the investor.
>> So, can I say if everybody wants to pull
out of that ETF, you're still safe?
>> Exactly. So, we keep a portion of the
fund unstaked, so it's immediately
liquid, and then we work with our
liquidity providers on any additional
top-up needs, and they would provide us
with that cash in the normal course of
business. So, you as an investor would
not experience anything, any
disruptions. We would be dealing with it
on the back end.
>> So, my final question, um, the
institutional appeal of your products is
obvious, but how would you convince a
retail crowd to look into ETHH or even
just any of your other Bitcoin products?
>> Yeah, we're actually doing an event, uh,
down the road today that we call Crypto
Connect, and it's geared towards
advisors and end clients, and our BTC
and ETH products are typically a really
big point of focus. They're, uh, very
low-cost ways to get into Bitcoin and
Ethereum, and if you look at some of the
trading costs that you might face on an
exchange to buy the spot representation,
it can be much higher than the spreads,
uh, and management fees of these
products. For example, I think sometimes
you can pay as much as 1 and 1/2% in
order to buy or sell a token on an
exchange versus a penny-wide spread to
buy or sell the ETF. They also have very
low management fees, and that's of
course a compelling feature.
>> And it's also a way to have access to
staked ETH without doing the staking
yourself.
>> Exactly. And to me, I think that's very
compelling. I'm not going to go out and
stake my, you know, like fractional
Ethereum token, but Grayscale is able to
do that and pass that on to the
investor.
>> I would love to know,
um, your due diligence process on how
quantum computer will affect Bitcoin and
the AI will break smart contracts.
>> Yeah. This is something that's been
coming up in a lot of cocktail
conversations here. Um, so I've heard
competing viewpoints. I've heard some
that think that that is going to be the
biggest threat to Bitcoin, and then I've
heard others that say these things are
already happening. AI is already
running. We already have these, uh, you
know, these models in place. So, I think
that it's something that should be paid
a lot of attention to. Um, I don't
necessarily have a thesis on if it's
going to break Bitcoin or not. I would I
hope that we get ahead of that, you
know. Um, but I think it's it's it's
something that we need to be vigilant
for and something that we should be
paying attention to.
>> How is the company dealing with it?
Like, what's the internal conversation?
>> Yeah. I think we're definitely, uh,
keeping we're monitoring it. And
something that we pay a lot of attention
to is also how could that affect our
service providers? So, we not only need
to view how it affects our immediate
workforce, but how does it also affect
some of our service providers like
custodians, authorized participants?
Like, could they suffer a hack? Um, so
we're getting in the weeds not only with
ourselves, but also with all of our
touch points.
>> Earlier, we're talking about, uh, a
conversation you had about Taipei, the
Taiwan exchange.
>> Yes.
>> What was that about?
>> Yeah, that was so interesting for me. I
went to a round table that Bloomberg
sponsored, and it was a way for US
issuers to learn about some of the
incentives to bring our products
overseas. Uh, and one such incentive was
an innovation kind of stipulation. Uh,
it seems that there's an appetite for
some of these covered call products that
we talked about. Now, I think that
digital asset covered calls might not
necessarily be the flavor that the
government is looking for, but it sounds
like there's a lot of encouragement for
innovation and something that I think
maybe we could look into pushing
forward.
>> Okay, well, thank you, Chris. That is
all the time we have.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> That was very insightful. Thank you.
>> Thanks so much.
>> Thank you. Do check out Grayscale
Investments. We'll put the link down
below.